[

](https://reason.com/)

### Reason's Annual Webathon is underway! Donate today to see your name here.

#### Reason is supported by:  
Jennifer Svahn & Jeff Nicastro

[

](https://reason.com/)[

](https://reason.com/)

Search for:  

### Login Form

Username/Email(Required)

Password(Required)

 Remember Me

Login        

Privacy Policy
==============

Effective: 10/10/2022

Reason Foundation is committed to protecting your privacy and taking great care of your personal information. Our Privacy Policy will help you understand what information we collect, how it is used, and how it is protected. If you have any questions, feel free to contact us at feedback@reason.org.

This Privacy Policy details our practices associated with the collection of your personally identifiable information ("**Personal Information**") in the course of your use of Reason.com or Reason.org ("Site"). This Privacy Policy does not apply to any other website that you access from our Site or that you use to access our Site from, which have data collection, storage and use practices and policies that may differ from this Privacy Policy.

**What Information We Collect**

**Personal Information we collect directly from you**

The Personal Information we may receive or may collect directly from you includes, without limitation, the following:

(1) contact data (such as your mailing or billing address, e-mail address, and phone number);

(2) demographic data (such as your gender, your date of birth and your zip code);

(3) payment data (such as a credit card number of payment account information); and

(4) other identifying information that you voluntarily choose to provide to us, such as unique identifiers like passwords, Personal Information in emails or letters that you send to us, and other information.

We may also collect additional information as described to you at the point of collection or pursuant to your consent. You may still access our Site if you choose not to provide us with any Personal Information, but if you elect not to share Personal Information it may affect our ability to provide products or services to you.

**Billing and payment information**

When you make a payment for subscriptions, donations, or other purposes through our Site, your payment card information is collected and stored by our payment processing partner. Our payment processing partner collects your voluntarily provided payment card information necessary to process your payment. Such partner's use and storage of information is governed by its applicable terms of service and privacy policy.

**Information we automatically collect when you use our site**

Some information, which may include Personal Information, may be automatically collected when you use our Site, such as the following: (i) IP address; (ii) domain server; (iii) type of device(s) used to access the Site; (iv) web browser(s) used to access the Site; (v) referring webpage or other source through which you accessed the Site; (vi) geolocation information; and (vii) other statistics and information associated with the interaction between your browser or device and the Site (collectively "**Traffic Data**"). Depending on applicable law, some Traffic Data may be Personal Information.

**How We Collect Information**

We collect information (including Personal Information and Traffic Data) when you use and interact with the Site, and in some cases from third party sources. Such means of collection include:

(1) When you use the Site to purchase products or services;

(2) When you voluntarily provide information in free-form text boxes through the Site or through responses to interviews, surveys, questionnaires, comments and the like;

(3) Through cookies, web beacons, analytics services and other tracking technology (collectively, "**Tracking Tools"**), as described below; and

(4) When you sign up to receive emails from us regarding events, products, specials or other marketing and promotional materials; and

(5) When you contact us.

**Tracking tools, behavioral advertising, and opt out options**

**Tracking tools:** We may use tools outlined below in order to provide our services to advertise to, and to better understand users.

 **(1) Cookies:** "Cookies" are small computer files transferred to your computing device that contain information such as user ID, user preferences, lists of pages visited and activities conducted while using the Services. We use cookies to improve or tailor the Services, customize advertisements by tracking navigation habits, measuring performance, and storing authentication status so re-entering credentials is not required, customize user experiences with the Services, and for analytics and fraud prevention. For more information on cookies, including how to control your cookie settings and preferences, visit [**http://www.allaboutcookies.org**](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Some cookies are placed by a third party on your device and provide information to us and third parties about your browsing habits (such as your visits to our Site, the pages you have visited, and the links and advertisements you have clicked). These cookies can be used to determine whether certain third-party services are being used, to identify your interests, and to serve advertisements relevant to you. We do not control third party cookies.

**(2) Web beacons:** "Web Beacons" (a.k.a. clear GIFs or pixel tags) are tiny graphic image files embedded in a web page or email that may be used to collect information about the use of our Site, the websites of selected advertisers and the emails, special promotions or newsletters that we send. The information collected by Web Beacons allows us to analyze how many people are using the Site, using selected publishers' websites or opening emails, and for what purpose, and also allows us to enhance our interest-based advertising (discussed further below).

**(3) Web service analytics:** We may use third-party analytics services in connection with the Site, including, for example, to register mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity and text typed into the Site. We use the information collected from these services to help make the Site easier to use and as otherwise set forth in the section called "How We Use Your Information." These analytics services generally do not collect Personal Information unless you voluntarily provide it and generally do not track your browsing habits across web services that do not use their services.

Reason.com uses Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting to track visitor demographics for the purposes of measuring the interest levels of various segments of our readership and engagement with website content. Reason does not link your reading history or other actions on Reason.com with personally identifiable information such as your name or email address. Visitors can opt-out of Google Analytics Demographic and Interest Reporting using [ad settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads).

**Behavioral advertising:** We may use a type of advertising commonly known as interest-based or online behavioral advertising. This means that some of our partners use Tracking Tools, such as cookies, pixel tags, and web beacons, to collect information about a user's online activities to display Reason ads to the user based on the user's interests ("**Behavioral advertising**"). Such partners may include third-party service providers, advertisers, advertising networks or platforms, traffic measurement service providers, marketing analytics service providers, and other third-party service providers (collectively, "**Advertising service providers**"). Other Tracking Tools used by our partners may collect information when you use the Site, such as IP address, operating system, browser, web page interactions, geographic location and demographic information, such as gender and age range. These Tracking Tools help us learn more about our users' demographics and internet behaviors.

**Options for opting out of cookies:** Many web browsers allow you to reject cookies or to alert you when a Cookie is placed on your computer.

You may opt out of receiving certain cookies and certain trackers by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) [**opt out page**](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) or the Digital Advertising Alliance (DAA) [**consumer opt-out page**](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/#completed). When you use these opt-out features, an "opt-out" Cookie will be placed on your computer. If you delete cookies on your computer, you may need to opt out again.

Even after opting out of Behavioral Advertising, you may still see Reason advertisements that are not interest-based (i.e., not targeted toward you). Also, opting out does not mean that Reason is no longer using Tracking Tools — we still may collect information about your use of the Site even after you have opted out of Behavioral Advertising and may still serve advertisements to you via the Site based on information it collects via the Site.

This Privacy Policy does not cover the use of cookies and other Tracking Tools by any third parties, and we aren't responsible for their privacy policies and practices. Please be aware that some cookies placed by third parties can continue to track your activities online even after you have left our Site.

**How we use your information**

We may use information that is not Personal Information that has been de-identified and/or aggregated to better understand who uses our Site and how we can deliver a better experience or otherwise at our discretion.

When you visit our website, log in, register or open an email, cookies, ad beacons, and similar technologies may be used by our online data partners or vendors to associate these activities with information they or others have about you, including your email address. We (or service providers on our behalf) may then send communications and marketing to these email addresses. You may opt out of receiving this advertising by visiting [https://app.retention.com/optout.](https://app.retention.com/optout)

We use information, including Personal Information, to provide and to help improve the Site, to develop new services, and to advertise (for example, to display Reason ads on other web services). Specifically, such use may include:

(1) Providing you with the products and information you request;

(2) Responding to correspondence that we receive from you;

(3) Contacting you when necessary or requested;

(4) Providing, maintaining, administering, or expanding the Site, performing business analyses, or for other internal purposes to support, improve or enhance our operations, the Site, and other products and services we offer;

(5) Customizing or tailoring your experience of the Site, which may include sending customized messages or showing you Sponsored Results;

(6) Notifying you about certain resources or services we think you may be interested in learning more about;

(7) Sending you information about our products or services;

(8) Sending emails and other communications that display content that we think will interest you and according to your preferences;

(9) Combining information received from third parties with information that we have from or about you and using the combined information for any of the purposes described in this Privacy Policy;

(10) Showing you advertisements, including interest-based or online behavioral advertising;

(11) Using statistical information that we collect in any way permitted by law, including from third parties in connection with their commercial and marketing efforts;

(12) Fulfilling our legally required obligations, such as preventing, detecting and investigating security incidents and potentially illegal or prohibited activities;

(13) Resolving disputes;

(14) Protecting against or deterring fraudulent, illegal, or harmful actions; and

(15) Enforcing our Terms of Service and other agreements.

**How we share your information**

In certain circumstances, and in order to provide you with our products of to perform the services, we may share certain information that we collect from you, as described in this section:

**(1) Advertising**: We do not sell email addresses to third parties. We may send email to you on behalf of paid advertisers.

**(2) Business partners**: We may share your Personal Information and/or Traffic Data with our partners who perform operational services (such as hosting, billing, fulfillment, data storage, security, insurance verification, web service analytics, or ad serving) and/or who make certain services, features, or functionality available to our users.

**(3) Cross device matching**: To determine if users have interacted with content across multiple devices and to match such devices, we work with partners who analyze device activity data and/or rely on your information (including demographic, geographic and interest-based data). To supplement this analysis, we also provide de-identified data to these partners. Based on this data, we may then display targeted advertisements across devices that we believe are associated or use this data to further analyze usage of Site across devices.

**(5) Public information and submissions**: You agree that any information that you may reveal in a review posting, online discussion, or forum is intended for the public and is not in any way private. Carefully consider whether to disclose any Personal Information in any public posting or forum. Your submissions may be seen and/or collected by third parties and may be used by others in ways we are unable to control or predict.

**(6) Other**: We also may be required to disclose your Personal Information or any other information we collect about you if we determine in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to: (1) comply with or fulfill our obligations under applicable law, regulation, court order or other legal process; (2) protect the rights, property or safety of you, Reason, or another party; (3) enforce this Privacy Policy, our Terms, or other agreements with you; or (4) respond to claims that any posting or other content violates third-party rights.

**Storage and security of information**

The security of your Personal Information is important to us. We endeavor to follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, both during transmission and in storage. For example, when you enter sensitive information on our Site and/or our Services, we encrypt that information (both at rest and in transit) using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

We store and process your information on our servers in the United States. We maintain industry standard backup and archival systems.

Although we make good faith efforts to store Personal Information in a secure operating environment that is not open to the public, we do not and cannot guarantee the security of your Personal Information. If at any time during or after our relationship we believe that the security of your Personal Information may have been compromised, we may seek to notify you of that development. If a notification is appropriate, we will endeavor to notify you as promptly as possible under the circumstances.  If we have your e-mail address, we may notify you by e-mail to the most recent e-mail address you have provided us in your account. Please keep your e-mail address in your account up to date. You can update that e-mail address anytime in your account. If you have difficulty updating your e-email address or other information on your account, please contact us at feedback@reason.org. You consent to our use of e-mail as a means of such notification. You may also use this e-mail address to request a print copy, at no charge, of an electronic notice we have sent to you regarding a compromise of your Personal Information.

 **Your privacy choices**

You can always opt not to disclose Personal Information to us, but keep in mind some Personal Information may be needed in order for you to use certain features of our Site.

Note that Reason cannot control or guarantee these rights with regard to Personal Information obtained by third parties who have requested and received your Personal Information through our Site and with your consent.

**How long we retain your information**

We retain Personal Information about you for as long as otherwise necessary to provide you the Services. In some cases, we retain Personal Information for longer, if doing so is necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes or collect fees owed, prevent fraud, enforce our Terms of Use of this Privacy Policy, or as otherwise permitted or required by applicable law, rule or regulation. Afterwards, we retain some information in a depersonalized or aggregated form but not in a way that would identify you personally.

**Other web services**

The Site may contain links to or embedded content from third party website or services. A link to or embedded content from a non-Reason website or service does not mean that we endorse that web service, the quality or accuracy of information presented on the non-Reason website or service or the persons or entities associated with the non-Reason website or service. If you decide to visit a third-party website or service, you are subject to the privacy policy of the third-party website or service as applicable, and we are not responsible for the policies and practices of the third-party website or service. We encourage you to ask questions before you disclose your information to others.

You may have arrived at the Site from a third-party website or service. The presence of such links or content on third-party website or service does not mean that we endorse that website or service, the quality or accuracy of information presented on the non-Reason website or service or the persons or entities associated with the non-Reason website or service. You may be subject to the privacy policy of the third-party website or service as applicable, and we are not responsible for the policies and practices of the third-party website or service. In addition, the policies, and practices of third parties do not apply to your information, including Personal Information, obtained pursuant to this Privacy Policy.

**Privacy Contact Information**  
If you have any questions, concerns, or comments about our privacy policy you may contact us using the information below:

By email: feedback@reason.org  
By phone: (310) 391-2245

We reserve the right to make changes to this policy. Any updates to this policy will be posted here and take effect on the date noted above.

This site is protected by reCAPTCHA and the Google [**Privacy Policy**](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and [**Terms of Service**](https://policies.google.com/terms) apply.

#### SHUT UP AND TAKE MY MONEY!

(You don't really have to shut up, but here's my money.)

#### HELP EXPAND _REASON_’S JOURNALISM

_Reason_ is an independent, audience-supported media organization. Your investment helps us reach millions of people every month.

#### I WANT FREE MINDS AND FREE MARKETS!

Help _Reason_ push back with more of the fact-based reporting we do best. Your support means more reporters, more investigations, and more coverage.

#### I’M SICK OF POLITICS AS USUAL

_Reason_ is the antidote to the same old stale take on ideas that actually matter to me.

#### FACTS ARE STUBBORN THINGS

_Reason_ pushes me to think critically with facts and analysis that shape my perspective and amplify the ideas I care about.

#### I WANT TO FUND FREE MINDS AND FREE MARKETS

Every dollar I give helps to fund more journalists, more videos, and more amazing stories that celebrate liberty.

#### I SUPPORT INDEPENDENT JOURNALISM!

It’s hard to trust the media these days, especially when everyone is pushing a partisan agenda. _Reason_ stands for my right to make my own choices.

[Yes, I want to make a difference for Free Minds and Free Markets!](https://reason.com/donate/?rfr=p0025&ip_creative_slot=popup&ip_creative_name=popup_25&ip_promotion_id=p0025&ip_promotion_name=webathon_2024&ip_item_name=donation) [No, I’ll follow the partisan herd](#)

#### POLITICS MAKES ME SO MAD!

_Reason_’s fearless, principled journalism keeps me sane in a crazy world.

[Making a donation to Reason right now will keep me from losing my mind!](https://reason.com/donate/?rfr=p0026&ip_creative_slot=popup&ip_creative_name=popup_26&ip_promotion_id=p0026&ip_promotion_name=webathon_2024&ip_item_name=donation) [No, I like being mad](#)

#### SUPPORT HONEST JOURNALISM

So much of the media tries telling you what to think. Support journalism that helps you to think for yourself.

#### MORE GOVERNMENT MEDDLING IN MY LIFE? NO THANKS.

Support the voices that advocate for your freedom. Donate to _Reason_ today!

[Yes, I want to make a difference for Free Minds and Free Markets!](https://reason.com/donate/?rfr=p0028&ip_creative_slot=popup&ip_creative_name=popup_28&ip_promotion_id=p0028&ip_promotion_name=webathon_2024&ip_item_name=donation) [No thanks](#)

#### PUSH BACK

Push back against misleading media lies and bad ideas. Support _Reason_’s journalism today.
